hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft almost
ran into a wall there this dude in here
is being so stubborn so stubborn he has
not given me anything not not one of you
wants to trade me the book that i want
but that's not what we're going to be
doing for the start of this episode we
are actually going to the end
i am sick of walking and boating around
i need to fly and this has come about
because good times with scar who is
actually online right now has messaged
me saying hey green let's go fly so i
have 53 levels as you can see and uh the
end is probably gonna be dangerous so i
want some backup gear i'm going to spend
these diamonds wisely
so going to make pretty much one of
everything again just in case something
horrible
horrible happens to me not bad i can put
those two together there we go 50 levels
down to 15 in a matter of seconds
however we have got at least one backup
tool of each
just in case we need it
i think i'm pretty much ready for the
end at this point i got some safety
blocks i've got some gear oh i got food
so i think what we'll do is we'll go and
meet up with scar and see what he's
doing also scar doesn't know that i've
got his door i don't think he's noticed
yet so
hopefully this will be the last time we
need to use the boat system around here
oh there he is
he's just just bobbing up and down how
are you doing scar are you ready to hit
the end
for all of its wings
i am very excited about the wings and to
make this trip successful i've actually
given you or have prepared for you some
magic crystals there you go some glass
just something
well i mean they're magic so it'll help
you with health it'll give you luck
health boost magic crystal see here it
says it says here minecraft colon red
stained glass and lime stained glass oh
that's just for the inspectors so they
think it's just standard glass because
they don't allow actual magic around
here so you know it's just a way around
do you want to see some real magic
yes wait that is real magic no no do you
want to see some real magic well that is
real magic but i'm interested in your
own okay
dead in the eyes
okay press f1 for me okay uh-huh you
pressed it
yeah
oh whoa whoa whoa whoa what in the world
wait
you just logged in
you just you tripped you literally
checked
what the heck
[Laughter]
i'm ready i'm ready for the trip now
that now i got you i'm ready for our
trip i've got some rockets for when we
got wings i've got some paper oh
i forgot about this bit all right let's
let's make our way over to the ball oh
wait wait i need to know i need to know
is there is it am i just crazy or do you
see an arrow too right yes
okay it has to be magic i mean this
whole this is a real magic this is this
is some this is some magic right here
i found it scott
[Music]
you got a b head too
we were so angry all right down we go i
think this is it i'm not entirely sure
but these are the right coordinates
please don't die
hold on
you're right in my blind spot
actually you know what you know what you
know what
i'm going to keep it on my hot bar and
i'm going to use it if i have to use it
because it's
it's going to be
it's going to be terrible oh wait for me
no don't no don't push me off the edge
okay okay well anyway bruh
i didn't do that did i no i did
come on let's let's get ourselves some
ender pearls and we need to find an end
city so i can i can look them dead in
the face with this one
i think so yeah it looks yeah i'm
looking at him dead i'm i see oh my
goodness that's terrifying
scott i did the last one you do it this
time
i'm scared just go we gotta we gotta
keep going this is ridiculous we've made
a lot of bridges we've traveled also a
very far
distance and we have no luck yet
yes
oh she's oh my gosh
no no no no no
you know
i'm a magic man but i'm not that magic
so the plan is
we find one elytra
and then that person will then take the
elytra and fly to the next end city and
bring back the second elytra do you have
your lucky crystal on you
uh
yeah
thank god you know no no no
dude that was magic man that's worth a
fortune of silver and gold you you you
you brought bad luck upon us no no no
we'll be fine
what could possibly go wrong
just hold at least hold the health one
my gosh okay
man
we need an auto shifter i see one i see
one okay don't get your hopes up like we
did last time this might not
oh
i'm not
i'm on my way and i'll start working on
the uh enrons because that's what we're
really here for
what oh i forgot about that
we got the city at the end of the game
did we win minecraft i think we just won
minecraft we didn't even kill the dragon
i got the electro
yeah nice
i've got two shocker boxes in the time
it's taken you to to look around for a
new end portal i have gone back to base
and enchanted this electro with
unbreaking and mending
um so do you know what i'm gonna fly
ahead i'm gonna find you in electra and
i'm gonna bring one back that little nod
there looks so
that little nod was so real yeah hold on
let me let me get you what you need here
there you go oh come on i just got rid
of these
oh there we go rockets okay here we go
i'm not the most conservative man with
rockets but i'll do my best all right
all right man uh
which way which way did we go last we
went south so i'm going to fly
north wish me luck
please tell me oh there's my i got it ah
scar
scott i found it i got it i got the one
i got the thing i got the the doodad
and
oh no you didn't lose it did you no i
just totally forgot about the uh the
ender dragon head i wanna take that
oh yeah i see the island i see the
island the sky where are you i'm here
you're
don't die what what happened no you
didn't go off the edge did you
no no no
it's been so long i want the feel of the
wind
we did it
we did it and we will never
do it again
have you seen my door by the way i lost
it no
someone take it
i i feel like there's a door abandoned
amongst us zombies can bring it down
there they went up the ladder no but
they could have like spawned up there
and then oh that's true that's true
that's true
dude are you ready to watch me fly for
the first time this season are you ready
for this
i'm ready
pumpkin bros
[Laughter]
i'm on the hunt for more doors
we're gonna create more door
but iskall is actually at his base but i
think this is all part of the fun so
i've got a plan i've scouted he's got a
spruce door and i have an idea on how to
get in and out asap pronto and get away
with it all but i need to get rid of
some of these items first okay i need to
dive in
and i'm going to replace his door with
two spruce trap doors and he won't even
realize where is he okay is that i'm
diving in silently silently silently
got the spruce door
close it up it's like
it's like i was never here
he doesn't
i think we might get away with that
we might have got away with that
mission success
job done
let's take this to the anvil
i think i need to know whose doors is
whose just for the time before i can
like get them all indexed i don't have a
single level
well all right then iskall
number one
because people are clearly gonna replace
their doors and i'm gonna have to keep
track now that i've got my elytra
finding everyone's base and stealing
their doors is going to be easy but you
know what
i'm not going to go out and just take
every single one i'm not going to go out
on a special mission just casually as
i'm there
where and when you might see me do this
just as i go into anyone's base i might
just go bop out i'll just take it and
that'll be it and i won't say anything
it would just be another one to the
collection but there's someone's that
has to be stolen simply because they
sent me on this ridiculous stupid task
and that is
mumbo
jumbo leo
and in his he still hasn't changed it oh
he's there
i think he
how long has he been there
he's just yeah he's just doing his thing
he's probably not even gonna notice
he is probably not gonna notice no
movement there we go i'm allowed to put
a sign down because he was the one that
sent me on this trip this trip in the
first place
is he really a completely afk
yeah i think i think he's really afk you
can see into his mustache
this is a
strange angle mambo i can see right up
your nose and we are out of here
now we can store our doors along with
the other one that's in here
ah
he's like looking at me like look in the
door he's like
mordor more like gondor
i'm sorry that's such a bad joke lord of
the rings reference everyone i'm sorry
i'm sorry if you haven't seen me
he is stolen my door okay come on out
you come let's have that door back
please thank you very much thank you
very much i think we're probably not
gonna store them in here to be honest i
am gonna i am gonna light this up though
boom right we'll pop this with all the
other i believe this was a scar door if
you have a look i have started naming
and storing all of them this is a scar
door number one i think i've been uh
collecting them look iskall two iskall
one mumbo one scar one oh wait i've got
two scar ones oh well well you can see
i've got some i've got some doors here
now i don't actually have enough space
to store all of these yet but that
brings me on to the big thing of today
which is i'm going to start working on
my bass in fact i've kind of already
started not this bass the the big bass
the proper bass this is just my starter
one to everyone's surprise i'm not
actually gonna make this in the jungle
i'm gonna make it in the ugly biome you
can see i've been lighting up the area
because this becomes
pretty much the worst place ever during
night and i've started moving over some
materials now it's very unlikely that
i'm going to get any progress done on
this place for a long time it's going to
take me a while to get cracking on this
now i'm going to take a screenshot of
this because
i want to draw
what i want to make here
and boom here it is there's that's what
i want to make this is a picture of this
of this same place and i want to create
a enormous
manner now obviously my drawing skills
are abysmal but you get the idea so i'm
going to need to terraform create
mountains and a higher level
up here so
the amount of resources that you need in
order to create even a small platform is
enormous and because it's going to be a
long time before we get there we really
need to invest first into our
infrastructure which i have been
steadily doing i have been manually
collecting
all of this sugarcane and i'll tell you
what actually i've had enough of it i'm
gonna take away the bottom layer of this
because i'm gonna collect it all up i'm
going to be making a proper sugarcane
farm so that i can trade all of this
stuff for emeralds but i've been
seriously debating whether to make my
sugarcane farm which is relatively big
in the very small starter base the
hobbit hole over here or do i actually
make it ahead of time i think i am i'm
gonna make it over here i'm just gonna
i'm gonna bury it it'll be on the
surface here but when all this
new terraforming that i just showed you
is gonna be done it will actually end up
being underground which is is pretty rad
and in order to make this sugar cane
farm i actually need it's the same one i
made last season so nothing super
exciting but i don't actually have any
slime so
for the first time i actually need to go
shopping i'm gonna take some diamonds
and we're gonna go and get the materials
that we need i have no idea what's
available in the shopping district but
i'm hoping that there is at least
something i can get
uh now that i'm flying i really hope
that there's some kind of rocket shop
because five five rockets isn't going to
get me there i don't think oh
oh look at this no i can't stop no
rockets
curiosity comes second to getting there
i'm so glad that i have elytra now there
we go we must be close because there's
the
starting island aha there is some
mycelium that is the shopping district
right here ah look at this
look at this
there's some what is that magic
honestly you think you've seen
everything on minecraft let alone
hermitcraft or minecraft you think
you've seen everything then all of a
sudden there's a pyramid made out of
magic what is that how is this possible
oh that's really weird oh that's really
weird look if you just go downwards like
okay that's strange oh a slime shop that
is exactly what we need this looks
just like iskall's uh style here so i
think this is probably a scale 32 slime
balls for one diamond that seems a
little steep if you ask me but i need a
few i guess it's early in this early
season prices you know what i mean uh i
don't know how much i need
gonna need a few blocks of it so that
should be enough for what we need what
else have we got in the shopping
district okay gotta not use my is there
a rocket shop uh books
i've spent so long on my villager farm
and elytra shop everything i've spent
time on preparing for
is for sale
how annoying is that do you know what
else we haven't even thought about
making a shop yet how have people got
such
they've got so many resources that
they're able to sell things now oh
that's a really cute effect let's have a
look what's
what is the mystery box of weird blocks
welcome to impulse's bedrock breaking
service for five diamonds impulse will
break a nether block in the ceiling
that's pretty cool i still want to know
what this is is this even a shop i don't
think this is a shop i think it's just
magic and here
dear hermits i hereby suggest that in
order to build a shop you pay for the
land you use by putting diamond blocks
here the pricing is 100 blocks x y
free y space one diamond block 100
blocks x divided by y no x time it must
be x by y so that's 10 that's a 10 by 10
space
is 100 blocks because 10 times 10 is 100
nice math screen okay well why don't we
go ahead and buy some prime real estate
straight away because obviously as time
goes on more and more space is going to
get bought
so if we just buy one two three
four
four yeah four hundred blocks that
should do it and then we need to choose
a nice space oh
this is so exciting there's so much
stuff everywhere that looks like a honey
shop
is that it no rocket shops okay i've got
four rockets to get home that's going to
be tough so we've got a 40 by 40 area
that we can use
actually
i'll tell you what we could do to save
diamond blocks we'll take three blocks
back we'll only buy a ten by ten and
what we'll do is we'll st
we'll stack our shops in order to save
some diamonds we'll stack our shops one
on top of the other and just use the
same real estate it'll be funny
obviously i can't i don't even have a
shop yet so i just want to choose a
space i think i'm going to take this
little area inside
inside of the water that i think that'll
be good okay that is a 10 by 10 100
block
space and i have no idea what we're
going to put in here but we're just
going to reserve it for now just in case
this is a prime piece of real estate
here it's a good investment i don't even
have any wood for a sign so well people
won't take it because obviously i've
marked this out so this is mine i claim
my territory
uh i got some slime blocks which is
actually what i really needed to make
sure that my farm works i just wish that
there was a rocket shop because we're
going to struggle to get back on four
rockets all right let's
let's go
i'm definitely not gonna make this i'm
gonna try and get as high as i can oh
boy ah i almost made it that's that
wasn't too bad four rockets and i pretty
much made it back okay now i've got the
materials the slime balls to make all of
the pistons
i think we're good to make this machine
now i just need to think carefully about
where to place this because obviously
i'm only building my base up there so i
might want to like tuck it in here
somewhere i don't really know i
i don't think forward enough for this
but i definitely want to pop it over
here so it's with all of my main base
infrastructure
yeah uh right let's get started
[Music]
this machine is
some kind of miracle i left it for an
hour and it is
full like properly full
i need i need better solutions to how to
store all this stuff
honestly this is insane i don't even
know what you do what do you do except
just chain these down like this
i don't even know the worst thing about
these machines is the noise
it's
so loud
it's really really loud but fortunately
i mean they're so efficient you don't
even have to run it for very long i
think i've made more sugarcane in half
an hour than i did for the entirety of
doing it by hand
so i'd call that mega successful now as
i said earlier gonna have lots of
terrain over the top of this so this
will get buried but the machine is there
and it is useful so even though we've
started a little bit of progress here
this is such a long-term project that
we'll still be working outside of the
hobbit hole sorry there's
there's a random pillar
what is scar doing what is scar doing oh
he's farming oh he's farming quartz hey
that's what i did when i was farming my
stuff great minds think alike scar
actually we better go and check if he's
got a door again because if he's got a
door again you know what we got to do he
probably won't even notice us passing by
if he's up there anyway we can get rid
of all this sugarcane now we do not need
this making it all ugly
of course he's got
of course he's got a door has he noticed
you know he's just digging away yep
we'll take his door put it with the rest
we've got a nice collection of doors
going on here i mean poor scar no one
else has had their doors stolen pretty
much just for people nearby but now i've
got my elytra i will be able to gather
everyone else's it's just the rocket
situation that is the problem i need me
some gunpowder but i'm thinking that
that's probably gonna have to wait for
next episode wait do i have to steal my
own door part of me says i've kind of
got to
but also
i don't wanna all right we'll leave them
for now but we'll add this door with the
rest scar door
number three i really need to sort out
where these are gonna go because they're
starting it's starting to pile up now oh
you know what i made this off camera and
i haven't even i haven't even shown it i
i yeah i made a super smelter in my
hobbit hole here i completely forgot to
even showcase this i mean it's not that
exciting it's just a bunch of furnaces
all linked up but
there's something weird going on here
and i can't figure out why
so making a super smelter is fairly easy
actually you just get you just link up
loads of hop it looks super complicated
but it's actually not too bad they they
all just um they all just travel through
here and the items fall down and then
there's a tiny amount of redstone that
goes along with it so
yeah it's not too difficult right the
issue that i don't understand
is one of them just won't work
professor beak
what do you think you'll do what do you
think you wanna you wanna sit on the
floor
all right you do you
all right let me show you so
if i put some coal in the top here so
that's needed no no no no no no no no no
no
i labeled it input and fuel why am i
doing the wrong thing right fuel in here
cobblestone in here
i've just i've got it yeah look this one
this one won't work
and i i it doesn't matter what i do
it just it just doesn't filter inside
here at all this makes no sense
absolutely
no sense to me at all
but whatever's going on here
it really doesn't matter because it does
churn out things pretty quickly once it
once it's got all everything it needs it
yeah it's pretty it's pretty good
so this small super smelter is going to
help me a lot with all of the projects
that i've got coming up
we've actually done a lot better this
season with the start of everything than
we ever have before like we got all the
materials for all the hoppers and such
we've collected many doors we've built a
bigger starter base than last time
and we've actually got ourselves a
villager hall all in like five episodes
this is insane
but now we need to get our
infrastructure sorted and then we can
start working on the big base over there
but i'm afraid
that is all for today's episode but i
have been extraordinarily busy with this
minecraft season so far and it's going
to stay that way so i shall see you in
the next episode
oh man there's still so much to do
good bye